Guide to the John S. Bradway Papers, 1914-1991 UA.29.02.0004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Volumes, 1922-1934
  Z volumes consist of John S. Bradway's correspondence during his tenure as Secretary of NALAO, and include correspondence with individuals and groups in cities and regions seeking to establish a legal aid society as well as existing legal aid societies.
  - NALAO documents Vol. 3, June-August, 1922 (Box 63)
    Scope and Contents note
    Legal aid material indicating work of Secretary
  - NALAO documents Vol. 4 (Box 63)
    Legal aid matters leading to the establishment of the NALAO on June 7, 1923
  - NALAO documents Vol. 5, 1923-1924 (Box 67)
    Early Work of the Committee on Records, on Relations with Social Agencies and on Domestic Relations Courts
  - NALAO documents Vol. 6 (Box 63)
    NALAO Miscellaneous Committees
    Relations with the Bar
    Small Loans
    Workmen's Compensation
    Committee on Wage Claims
  - NALAO documents Vol. 7 (Box 64)
    Committee on the Public Defender
  - NALAO documents Vol. 8 (Box 64)
    Papers and Speeches
  - NALAO documents Vol. 9 (Box 64)
    International legal aid work
  - NALAO documents Vol. 13 (Box 64)
    N.Y. Legal Aid Societies
    Brief: Klein vs. Hultun, North Dakota Supreme Court
    Paper: "Legal Aid Work-A Social Service"
    International Legal Aid Work
  - NALAO documents Vol. 14 (Box 64)
    Newspapers Clippings
    Specific Legal Societies
  - NALAO documents Vol. 15 (Box 64)
    Miscellaneous documents relating to various NALAO committees
  - NALAO documents Vol. 18 (Box 64)
    NALAO Papers by the Secretary
    Miscellaneous Reports
  - NALAO documents Vol. 19 (Box 65)
    Figures of Legal Aid Organizations, 1927
  - NALAO documents Vol. 22 (Box 65)
    Biographical material on heads of NALAO member organizations (includes photographs)
  - NALAO documents Vol. 23 (Box 65)
  - NALAO documents Vol. 25, 1929-1930 (Box 65)
    Figures of Legal Aid Organizations
  - NALAO documents Vol. 26, 1930-1931 (Box 65)
  - NALAO documents Vol. 27 (Box 65)
    Figures of Legal Aid Organizations, 1931-1932
  - NALAO documents Vol. 28 (Box 65)
    Figures of Legal Aid Organizations, 1932-1933
  - NALAO documents Vol. 29 (Box 66)
    NALAO Bulletins Nos. 1-38
  - NALAO documents Vol. 31, 1932-1934 (Box 66)
    NALAO Committee Reports
  - Ellis Estate: Vol. 3: Miscellaneous Data Collected (Box 63)
  - Ellis Estate: Vol. 4: Material Relating to Waiting Lists (Box 63)
  - Ellis Estate: Vol. 6: Reports of Similar Cases (Box 63)
  - Z Vol. 3, 1922-1930 (Box 37)
    Legal Aid Work of Clinic at Univ. of Southern California
    Memphis Legal Aid Society
    Social Welfare League, Seattle, WA
  - Z Vol. 4, 1923-1929 (Box 39)
    Material on International Law
    Paper: "Public Legal Aid Work"
    International Migration Service
    Paper: "Does the Law Provide Adequate Protection for Beneficiaries of Charitable Trusts?"
    Paper: "Charitable Trust of Charles E. Ellis"
  - Z Vol. 5, 1923-1930 (Box 41)
    Parents' Council of Philadelphia
    Reading, PA Welfare Federation
    Paper on: Average Man and his Chance in our Courts
  - Z Vol. 6, 1925-1931 (Box 39)
    Collections Judgements
    Welfare Federation of Cleveland
    Conciliation Courts
    Boston Legal Aid Society-Workmen's Compensation
  - Z Vol. 7, 1925-1932 (Box 41)
    National Conference of Social Work
    American Bar Association
    Correspondence with Alice Waldo
    Paper: "Legal-social Investigation"
    Child Welfare League of America
  - Z Vol. 8, 1928-1932 (Box 40)
    Draft of Handbook of Legal Aid Work
    Books and Articles on Legal Aid Work
    National Social Work Council
  - Z Vol. 9, 1922-1932 (Box 41)
    Legal Aid Society, Cincinnati
    Pennsylvania Bar Association
    National Probation Association
  - Z Vol. 10, 1923-1931 (Box 41)
    White House Conference on Child Health and Protection
    Minimum Statistics
    Papers: "Arbitration of Small Claims as a Relief for Court Congestion"; "The Massachusetts Workmen's Compensation Act in Action"
  - Z Vol. 11, 1922-1931 (Box 48)
    Chicago Legal Aid Society
    Handbook Correspondence
  - Z Vol. 12, 1922-1931 (Box 42)
    Legal Aid Societies, Cleveland and Albany
    Re: Legal Aid Work for Chinese
    Reports
  - Z Vol. 13, 1922-1929 (Box 43)
    Children's Bureau-Philadelphia
    Paper: "Co-operation of Legal Aid Societies and labor Commission in the Collection of Unpaid Wages"
    Legal Aid Society of N.Y.C.
  - Z Vol. 14, 1922-1931 (Box 44)
    American Institute of Criminal Law and Criminology
    Phi Delta Phi
    Bradway Paper: "Legal Internship"
    Legal Aid Society of Cincinnati
    Paper: "Unemployment as seen by Legal Aid Societies"
    Address: "The Prisoner at the Bar"
    Correspondence concerning Annals
    Paper: "Case of the Dead Hand"
    Correspondence with the Legal Aid Dept. of the Jewish Social Service Bureau of Chicago
  - Z Vol. 15, 1922-1931 (Box 45)
    League of Nations, 1925
    Material on Political Science Course
    Outline of textbook for Law Students in Legal Clinics
    Southern California Legal Aid Clinic Association
    Correspondence with Reginald Smith
    Small Loan law
    Loan Sharks
  - Z Vol. 16, 1922-1929 (Box 46)
    Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1923
    Correspondence with Laura Spelman Rockefeller Assocation
    New NALAO Constitution, 1925-1928
    Paper: "An Analysis of the Legal Cases of The International Migration Service"
    Draft of Report of Joint Committee on Domestic Relations Court
    League of Nations, International Arrangements for Legal Assistance for the Poor
    Paper: "Legal Aid Statistics and What they Show"
  - Z Vol. 17, 1927-1931 (Box 47)
    Preliminary notes and materials in preparation for book Bar and Public Relations
  - Z Vol. 18, 1928-1933 (Box 48)
    Chicago University: School of Social Service Administration
    Paper: "The Purpose and Nature of Courses in Law for Social Workers"
  - Z Vol. 19, 1923-1930 (Box 48)
    Family Service Society of Canton, OH
    Legal Aid Work: Columbus, Cincinnati, Cleveland, Toledo
    Correspondence, Greensboro, N.C.
  - Z Vol. 20, 1922-1930 (Box 48)
    Legal Aid Society of Pittsburgh
    Public Charities Association of Pennsylvania
    Legal Aid Society of Denver
    Social Service Bureau-Pontiac, MI
  - Z Vol. 21, 1922-1929 (Box 49)
    Dept. of Public Welfare-Bureau of Legal Aid, Philadelphia
    Correspondence with Roman Hassrick; The Annals
    Voluntary Defenders Committee
    Paper: "Desirability of a Public Defender"
    Address: "Progress of Legal Aid Work in Pennsylvania"
    Paper: "Legal Aid and Its Proper Relation to Members of the Bar"
  - Z Vol. 22, 1922-1930 (Box 50)
    U.S. Dept. of Labor
    Children's Bureau
    Bureau of Labor Statistics
    Establishment of Legal Aid Organization in Washington
    Correspondence with W.H. Taft
    Family Welfare Assoc. of N.Y.C.
    Voluntary Defenders Committee of the Legal Aid Society
  - Z Vol. 23, 1923-1929 (Box 50)
    Legal Aid Society of San Francisco
    Public Defender of Los Angeles
    Legal Aid Bureau of Indiana
    Legal of Bureau of Chicago-Criminal Courts Bureau
  - Z Vol. 24, 1922-1930 (Box 50)
    Handbook of Legal Aid Work
    Legal Aid Newsletter and Misc. Correspondence
    Legal Aid Society of Rhode Island
    Creation of Newport, R.I. Legal Aid Council
    Russel Sage Foundation
    Charity Organization Society of Yonkers, N.Y.
  - Z Vol. 25, 1923-1931 (Box 50)
    Correspondence with R.H. Smith (1930-1931), with Boston Legal Aid Society (1924-1930), and with Legal Aid Bureau of Detroit Bar Association (1923-1929). Also Boston Legal Society reports 1925, 1926, and 1927.
  - Z Vol. 26, 1922-1931 (Box 51)
    Correspondence while in Southern California (1928-1930), with E. Fabre Surveyor, with George H. Corbett of Montreal Legal Aid Bureau (1923-1931), with John F. Forward, Public Defender of Hartford, Conn., with Justin Miller (1927-1929), with Birmingham, Ala. (1923-1929), with San Diego, Cal. (1922-1929), with Connecticut, and others.
  - Z Vol. 27, 1923-1931 (Box 51)
    Correspondence with Carl Wheaton
    Preliminary draft of Committee on Curriculum
    Memo to Dean Hale-Univ. of Southern California
    General Correspondence with Univ. of Southern California faculty
  - Z Vol. 28, 1922-1929 (Box 51)
    Courts Committee of Brooklyn Bureau of Charity
    National Desertion Bureau
    Welfare Council of N.Y.C.
    Louis Fabricant
    Legal Aid Bureau of Buffalo
    Paper: "Legal Aid in Richmond"
  - Z Vol. 29, 1922-1930 (Box 51)
    Correspondence with W.W. Cook of Johns Hopkins University (1929), with New Orleans, LA (1922-1930), with Louisville, KY (1923-1929), with Atlanta Legal Aid Society (1925-1928), and other materials.
  - Z Vol. 30, 1929-1931 (Box 52)
    Pennsylvania Legal Aid Organizations
    National Conference on Social Work
    Correspondence with Justin Miller concerning establishment of Legal Aid Clinic at Duke, 1930-1931
  - Z Vol. 31, 1927-1933 (Box 53)
    American Association for Labor Legislation
    American Social Hygiene Association
    Foreign Language Information Service
    Family Welfare Association
    National Crime Commission
    NALAO Committees
  - Z Vol. 32 (Box 54)
    Compis Juris of Legal Aid (outline)
    Incorporation of NALAO
    Case load questionnaire
    Treasurer's Reports, 1927-1929
    Member Reports
  - Z Vol. 33 (Box 54)
    -Pennsylvania: Pottsville, Scranton, Towanda, Wilkes-Barre
    Pennsylvania Prison Society
    Rhode Island Legal Aid Society
  - Z Vol. 34, 1924-1933 (Box 54)
    Philadelphia: Legal Aid Bureau, Voluntary Defenders Committee
    Buffalo Legal Aid Society
    Philadelphia Conference of Social Work
  - Z Vol. 35, 1922-1933 (Box 55)
    Legal Aid Bureau of the Educational Alliance of N.Y.
    N.Y. Legal Aid Society
    N.Y. Section of the National Council of Jewish Women
  - Z Vol. 36 (Box 54)
    Correspondence with S.C., Tenn., Tex., Utah, Va., Wa., W.V., Wisc., Australia, Belgium, and the League of Nations
  - Z Vol. 37, 1923-1931 (Box 56)
    NALAO Financial Material
    NALAO Committee on Records
    Biographical Material on Members
  - Z Vol. 38, 1922-1933 (Box 57)
    Correspondence, N.J., Neb., N.Y. Legal Aid Society, N.Y. Voluntary Defenders Committee
  - Z Vol. 39, 1922-1933 (Box 58)
    Correspondence, Legal Aid Societies in Mich., Minn., Miss., Missouri, Mont.
  - Z Vol. 40, 1929-1931 (Box 59)
    NALAO Executive Committee
    National Handbook
    Committee on Domestic Relations Courts
  - Z Vol. 41, 1922-1933 (Box 60)
    Harvard Legal Aid Bureau
    Boston Legal Aid Society
    Correspondence, Mass. and Mich.
  - Z Vol. 42, 1924-1933 (Box 60)
    Interracial Commission
    N.C. Bar Association
    General N.C. Correspondence
    General Correspondence, Ohio, Okla., N.D., Ore., Cincinnati, Dayton, Cleveland
  - Z Vol. 43, 1929-1931 (Box 60)
    Auto chattel foreclosure
    International Legal Aid Committee
  - Z Vol. 44, 1929-1933 (Box 60)
    NALAO Financial material
    Child Welfare League
  - Z Vol. 45, 1924-1933 (Box 61)
    Correspondence, Stockholm, India, Milwaukee, England, Honolulu, and Manila
  - Z Vol. 46, 1930-1933 (Box 62)
    Treasurer's Report
    Brief on Question: "Are Legal Aid Societies Engaged in Unlawful Practice of the Law?"
  - Z Vol. 47, 1928-1932 (Box 62)
    Correspondence re: Bulletins
    Functions of Legal Aid Societies
    Suggested outline of case studies book
  - Z Vol. 48, 1928-1932 (Box 62)
    W. Bruce Coble
    National Symbol
  - Z Vol. 49, 1930-1933 (Box 62)
    Financial Problems
    Detailed Statistics
    Complaints
    Biographical Material
- Accession UA2017.0063, 3
  - Files, 1
    - Articles pertaining to Bradway either specifically or indirectly, and to legal aid clients, 1922-1974 (Box 68)
    - "The Final Examination", 1930 (Box 68)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943, undated (Box 68)
    - "The Existing Need for the Improved Training of College and University Graduates (as Undergraduates) in the Use of Basic English Accuracy", A.C. Jordan, 1955 December 29 (Box 68)
    - Notes on Final Exams, 1970-1972 (Box 68)
    - California Western Law Review Tributes to Bradway & "The Legally Underprivileged", 1974 (Box 68)
      2 folders
    - Duke Legal Aid Clinic Materials, 1977-1997 (Box 68)
    - "Bradway Bequest Benefits LEAP" - TempleEsq., 1991 Spring (Box 68)
    - Death Notice, Will, Obituaries, Resume, 1985 (Box 68)
    - Tommie Stanley Correspondence with John M. Lindsey, 1985-1991 (Box 68)
    - Pre-Law School Program, 1985 (Box 68)
    - Digitized photographs, undated; 17 files, approximately 30 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA29020004-SET-0001, Disk UA29020004-USB-0001, Box Digital Media Box 10)
      Digital photographs in JPEG format. Also included is a MS Word document describing the photographs.
  - Writings, 2
    - California Western Law Review "The Unending Quest", 1965 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Bar" - draft of the beginning material, chapter synopses, 1979 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Ba"r - manuscript submissions for publication, 1982 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Bar" - stages II and III, 1982 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Bar" - stages IV and V, ca. 1982 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Bar" - stage VI, 1982 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Bar" - finished typing, 1978 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Bar" #1, 1978 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Bar" #2, 1978 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Bar" #3, ca. 1978 (Box 68)
    - "A Concise Biography of the American Bar" #4, 1978 (Box 68)
    - Duke Legal Aid Clinic Materials (1 of 5), undated (Box 69)
    - Duke Legal Aid Clinic Materials (2 of 5), undated (Box 69)
    - Duke Legal Aid Clinic Materials (3 of 5), undated (Box 69)
    - Duke Legal Aid Clinic Materials (4 of 5), undated (Box 69)
    - Duke Legal Aid Clinic Materials (5 of 5), undated (Box 69)
    - Selected Materials of Legal Aid Clinic Drills: Duke University, 1959 (Box 68)
    - assorted writings, 1958, 1978 (Box 68)
      "The History of a Lawsuit," "Bradway--Stretch--Keasby--Waddington Families"
    - assorted writings, 1966, 1969, 1976 (Box 68)
      "Two's Company," "Restraints: A Proposal for a Student Code of Ethics," Introduction in "Progress in Family Law"
    - assorted writings, 1970-1970, 1983, undated (Box 68)
      "A Note on Improving the Relationship Between Attorney and Client," "An Ounce of Prevention," "Chasing Legal Education: The Fourth Viewpoint," "The Legal Profession Course"
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1976, 1979, 1981 (Box 68)
      "A Public Image for the Bar," "Disaster by Decree: The Supreme Court Decisions on Race and the School," "A Note on Improving the Relationship Between Attorney and Client," "Legal-Aid Work in the Law Schools"